Subject Files
Marist Archives and Special Collections
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6
  - Subject files: High Adventure with Lowell Thomas (Alaska), 1958 October; 4 (Box 1548)
    - HIGH FLIERS - Daring every-day escapades of fearless Alaskan bush pilots are dramatically depicted in the first edition (Alaska-America's Last Frontier) of the new "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" video series in full color over the CBS television network Wednesday, October 8th from 8:00 to 9:00 p.m., Eastern Daylight Time. Here, Lowell Thomas disembarks on the tricky Alaska ice pack from a light plane piloted by Merrill Wien, one of the best-known of the Alaskan daredevils whose exploits will make armchair adventurers sit up and take notice. Because of the lack of railroads and highways, the plane is the most used transportation vehicle nowadays in the land of the midnight sun. "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" is sponsored by the United Motors System and Delco-Remy Division of General Motors, 16
    - Note: [press release] HIGH FLIERS - Daring every-day escapades of fearless Alaskan bush pilots are dramatically depicted in the first edition (Alaska-America's Last Frontier) of the new "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" video series in full color over the CBS television network Wednesday, October 8th from 8:00 to 9:00 p.m., Eastern Daylight Time. Here, Lowell Thomas disembarks on the tricky Alaska ice pack from a light plane piloted by Merrill Wien, one of the best-known of the Alaskan daredevils whose exploits will make armchair adventurers sit up and take notice. Because of the lack of railroads and highways, the plane is the most used transportation vehicle nowadays in the land of the midnight sun. "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" is sponsored by the United Motors System and Delco-Remy Division of General Motors, 17
    - [Two men standing outside of a plane in Alaska; from Lowell Thomas's High Adventure], 18
    - [Two men pitching a tent during Lowell Thomas's High Adventure in Alaska], 19
    - [A man standing by a plane on a marsh in Alaska; taken during Lowell Thomas's High Adventure in Alaska], 20
    - [Two men standing by their tent and plane in Alaska; taken during Lowell Thomas's High Adventure in Alaska], 21
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. and wife, 22
    - Verso: Thos, Jr., + wife, 22-verso
  - Subject files: High Adventure with Lowell Thomas (Danger Island), 1959 January; 5 (Box 1548)
    - DANGER FLIGHT - Lowell Thomas dons lifejacket before leaving by helicopter from the deck of the USS Point Defiance for first look at Danger Island (Puka Puka), tiny coral atoll in the South Pacific, which is the scene for the third edition of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" to be colorcast over the CBS television network, Monday, January 19th, from 10:00 to 11:00 p.m., EST. Later, Thomas landed on the island with 32 famous scientists to check reactions of the sun by outer space rockets during the solar eclipse of October 12th, 1
    - Note: [press release] DANGER FLIGHT - Lowell Thomas dons lifejacket before leaving by helicopter from the deck of the USS Point Defiance for first look at Danger Island (Puka Puka), tiny coral atoll in the South Pacific, which is the scene for the third edition of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" to be colorcast over the CBS television network, Monday, January 19th, from 10:00 to 11:00 p.m., EST. Later, Thomas landed on the island with 32 famous scientists to check reactions of the sun by outer space rockets during the solar eclipse of October 12th, 2
    - UNUSUAL ROLE - Lowell Thomas (back row, center) officiates as King Neptune during ceremonies initiating "pollywogs" (first-time crossers of the Equator) into "shellbacks" aboard USS Point Defiance, which carried him and 32 world-famed American scientists to remote Puka Puka, or Danger Island, in the South Seas for one of the most important projects of the International Geophysical Year. Colorful, exciting activities on the island are main feature of the third installment of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" coming to TV screens in full color over the CBS network Monday, January 19th, from 10:00 to 11:00 p.m., EST. "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" is sponsored by the United Motors System and Delco-Remy Division of General Motors, 3
    - Note: [press release] UNUSUAL ROLE - Lowell Thomas (back row, center) officiates as King Neptune during ceremonies initiating "pollywogs" (first-time crossers of the Equator) into "shellbacks" aboard USS Point Defiance, which carried him and 32 world-famed American scientists to remote Puka Puka, or Danger Island, in the South Seas for one of the most important projects of the International Geophysical Year. Colorful, exciting activities on the island are main feature of the third installment of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" coming to TV screens in full color over the CBS network Monday, January 19th, from 10:00 to 11:00 p.m., EST. "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" is sponsored by the United Motors System and Delco-Remy Division of General Motors, 4
    - SHIP TO SHORE - On board USS Point Defiance in the South Seas, preparatory to debarking to the lonely isle of Puka Puka, or Danger Island, Lowell Thomas (r.) confers with Dr. Friedman, one of the leaders of the 32-man Naval Research Laboratory scientific expedition, which used the island as headquarters to study the sun during the October 12th solar eclipse. Activities of the scientists on this by-passed coral atoll inhabited by a few hundred Polynesians, who have had little or no previous contact with the outer world, make for dramatic contrast in the third edition in color of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas," which will be telecast over the CBS-TV network, Monday, January 19th, from 10:00-11:00 p.m., EST, 5
    - Note: [press release] SHIP TO SHORE - On board USS Point Defiance in the South Seas, preparatory to debarking to the lonely isle of Puka Puka, or Danger Island, Lowell Thomas (r.) confers with Dr. Friedman, one of the leaders of the 32-man Naval Research Laboratory scientific expedition, which used the island as headquarters to study the sun during the October 12th solar eclipse. Activities of the scientists on this by-passed coral atoll inhabited by a few hundred Polynesians, who have had little or no previous contact with the outer world, make for dramatic contrast in the third edition in color of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas," which will be telecast over the CBS-TV network, Monday, January 19th, from 10:00-11:00 p.m., EST, 6
    - HOWDY, FOLKS - Lowell Thomas waves "howdy" while standing beside a Nike-Asp rocket on board the USS Point Defiance which transported the explorer and 32 scientists to the lonely isle of Puka Puka, or Danger Island, in the South Seas, scene of the third edition of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" to be colorcast over the CBS-TV network Monday, January 19th, 10:00-11:00 p.m., EST under the auspices of the United Motors System and Delco-Remy Division of General Motors. Puka Puka, directly in the path of the October 12th solar eclipse, was used by the scientists as headquarters to study the sun under eclipse conditions as one of the most important projects of the International Geophysical Year. The "Sadie Thompson" rocket was one of the six fired 150 miles into outer space to observe the sun from that vantage point during the eclipse totality. Besides the activity on Danger Island, Samoa, Tahiti and other South Sea spots are featured in the forthcoming "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas", 7
    - Note: [press release] HOWDY, FOLKS - Lowell Thomas waves "howdy" while standing beside a Nike-Asp rocket on board the USS Point Defiance which transported the explorer and 32 scientists to the lonely isle of Puka Puka, or Danger Island, in the South Seas, scene of the third edition of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" to be colorcast over the CBS-TV network Monday, January 19th, 10:00-11:00 p.m., EST under the auspices of the United Motors System and Delco-Remy Division of General Motors. Puka Puka, directly in the path of the October 12th solar eclipse, was used by the scientists as headquarters to study the sun under eclipse conditions as one of the most important projects of the International Geophysical Year. The "Sadie Thompson" rocket was one of the six fired 150 miles into outer space to observe the sun from that vantage point during the eclipse totality. Besides the activity on Danger Island, Samoa, Tahiti and other South Sea spots are featured in the forthcoming "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas", 8
    - DANGER ISLAND HEADQUARTERS - This is the camp set up for 32 American scientists by the U. S. Navy on Puka Puka, or Danger Island, in the uncharted South Seas, scene of the third installment of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (in color, CBS-TV, Monday, January 19th, 10:00-11:00 p.m., EST). One of the most important projects of the International Geophysical Year, scientists used jet-age instruments, including rockets launched 150 miles into outer space, to record activities of the sun during the October 12th eclipse. Navy frogmen were forced to blast a channel through dangerous reef to land supplies on the seldom-visited island. This and other dramatic incidents are featured in the "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" show, which is sponsored by the United Motors System and Delco-Remy Division of General Motors, 9
    - Note: [press release] DANGER ISLAND HEADQUARTERS - This is the camp set up for 32 American scientists by the U. S. Navy on Puka Puka, or Danger Island, in the uncharted South Seas, scene of the third installment of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (in color, CBS-TV, Monday, January 19th, 10:00-11:00 p.m., EST). One of the most important projects of the International Geophysical Year, scientists used jet-age instruments, including rockets launched 150 miles into outer space, to record activities of the sun during the October 12th eclipse. Navy frogmen were forced to blast a channel through dangerous reef to land supplies on the seldom-visited island. This and other dramatic incidents are featured in the "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" show, which is sponsored by the United Motors System and Delco-Remy Division of General Motors, 10
    - CONFERENCE, SOUTH SEAS STYLE - Against the backdrop of a bungalow built of packing cases on the little coral atoll of Puka Puka, or Danger Island, in the remote South Seas, Lowell Thomas (r.) holds a production conference concerning the third episode of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (in color, CBS-TV, Monday, January 19th, 10:00-11:00 p.m., EST) with Technicians (l. to r.) Bert Gerard, Roger Bulov and Director Bob Young. Crew were on the island to photograph activities of 32 American scientists, transported there by U. S. Naval Research Laboratory to study sun rays, sun flares, sun spots, etc. during the October 12th eclipse. Project was considered one of the most important of the International Geophysical Year, 11
    - Note: [press release] CONFERENCE, SOUTH SEAS STYLE - Against the backdrop of a bungalow built of packing cases on the little coral atoll of Puka Puka, or Danger Island, in the remote South Seas, Lowell Thomas (r.) holds a production conference concerning the third episode of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (in color, CBS-TV, Monday, January 19th, 10:00-11:00 p.m., EST) with Technicians (l. to r.) Bert Gerard, Roger Bulov and Director Bob Young. Crew were on the island to photograph activities of 32 American scientists, transported there by U. S. Naval Research Laboratory to study sun rays, sun flares, sun spots, etc. during the October 12th eclipse. Project was considered one of the most important of the International Geophysical Year, 12
    - EXOTIC BELLE - "Whiskey Johnnie" (that's her real name) Frisbie, half-native daughter of the legendary South Seas author, Rober Dean Frisbie, performs in an Hawaiian night club for opening scenes in the third episode of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (in color, CBS-TV, Monday, January 19th, 10:00-11:00 p.m., EST). Thomas stopped off to interview "Whiskey Johnnie" about the little, unknown island of Puka Puka, or Danger Island, in the South Seas, where she was born and which is the backdrop for the next "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" show. The island, virtually cut off from civilization for centuries because its dangerous reef barred all vessels became the headquarters of a group of scientists from the U.S., transported there by the U. S. Navy to gather valuable knowledge about the sun during the October 12th eclipse. Six Nike-asp rockets launched 150 miles into space used in the observations. Titled "Danger Island," the Thomas one-hour film in color will highlight this and other dramatic events on the island during the IGY project. "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" is sponsored by the United Motors System and Delco-Remy Division of General Motors, 13
    - Note: [press release] EXOTIC BELLE - "Whiskey Johnnie" (that's her real name) Frisbie, half-native daughter of the legendary South Seas author, Rober Dean Frisbie, performs in an Hawaiian night club for opening scenes in the third episode of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (in color, CBS-TV, Monday, January 19th, 10:00-11:00 p.m., EST). Thomas stopped off to interview "Whiskey Johnnie" about the little, unknown island of Puka Puka, or Danger Island, in the South Seas, where she was born and which is the backdrop for the next "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" show. The island, virtually cut off from civilization for centuries because its dangerous reef barred all vessels became the headquarters of a group of scientists from the U.S., transported there by the U. S. Navy to gather valuable knowledge about the sun during the October 12th eclipse. Six Nike-asp rockets launched 150 miles into space used in the observations. Titled "Danger Island," the Thomas one-hour film in color will highlight this and other dramatic events on the island during the IGY project. "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" is sponsored by the United Motors System and Delco-Remy Division of General Motors, 14
    - [Lowell Thomas standing with the natives during his High Adventure to Danger Island], 15
  - Subject files: High Adventure with Lowell Thomas (From the Persian Gulf to Zanzibar), 1959 March; 6 (Box 1548)
    - THEY GO TO HIS HEAD - Lowell Thomas, distinguished explorer and commentator whose next "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" TV show will be beamed over the CBS Television network on Friday, March 27th, 8:00-9:00 p.m., EST, is a hat collector. During his myriad wanderings around the world, Thomas has amassed an amazing collection of strange and exotic headgear which is stored in a special building on his estate near Pawling, N. Y. Thomas is shown here with a small part of his collection. Although he could get heady making a choice from the hundreds of hats he has on hand, Lowell, prefers the light gray Texas-type headpiece shown on the far right, 1
    - Note: [press release] THEY GO TO HIS HEAD - Lowell Thomas, distinguished explorer and commentator whose next "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" TV show will be beamed over the CBS Television network on Friday, March 27th, 8:00-9:00 p.m., EST, is a hat collector. During his myriad wanderings around the world, Thomas has amassed an amazing collection of strange and exotic headgear which is stored in a special building on his estate near Pawling, N. Y. Thomas is shown here with a small part of his collection. Although he could get heady making a choice from the hundreds of hats he has on hand, Lowell, prefers the light gray Texas-type headpiece shown on the far right, 2
    - ENDED RIGHT HERE - Back in the United States, Lowell Thomas points out the exotic island of Zanzibar, final port of call on a 3,500-mile ocean trip in an ancient Arabian dhow along the Arabian and East African coasts from Bahrein on the Persian Gulf. The exciting fourth installment of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" will be colorcast over the CBS television network Friday, March 27th, 8:00-9:00 p.m., EST, under the sponsorship of the United Motors System and Delco-Remy Division of General Motors. It took the sail-driven dhow a month to make the voyage. Besides life on the dhow, the next "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" also will display other thrill-packed sequences such as a falcon hunt in southern Arabia, a pearl diving expedition in the Persian Gulf, a turtle hunt along Africa's east coast and a novel bullfight in Zanzibar where the bull always wins!, 3
    - Note: [press release] ENDED RIGHT HERE - Back in the United States, Lowell Thomas points out the exotic island of Zanzibar, final port of call on a 3,500-mile ocean trip in an ancient Arabian dhow along the Arabian and East African coasts from Bahrein on the Persian Gulf. The exciting fourth installment of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" will be colorcast over the CBS television network Friday, March 27th, 8:00-9:00 p.m., EST, under the sponsorship of the United Motors System and Delco-Remy Division of General Motors. It took the sail-driven dhow a month to make the voyage. Besides life on the dhow, the next "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" also will display other thrill-packed sequences such as a falcon hunt in southern Arabia, a pearl diving expedition in the Persian Gulf, a turtle hunt along Africa's east coast and a novel bullfight in Zanzibar where the bull always wins!, 4
    - TOPS ANYTHING FOR STYLE - Lowell Thomas, whose next "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" show will be seen in full color over the CBS television network Friday, March 27, 8:00-9:00 p.m., EST, has one of the world's finest collection of hats garnered during his travels to every nook and cranny of the glove. Thomas says that one of the most becoming hats on all men is this Persian lamb headgear which was given to him by one of the fierce tribal chiefs in the mountainous country of Afghanistan, 5
    - Note: [press release] TOPS ANYTHING FOR STYLE - Lowell Thomas, whose next "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" show will be seen in full color over the CBS television network Friday, March 27, 8:00-9:00 p.m., EST, has one of the world's finest collection of hats garnered during his travels to every nook and cranny of the glove. Thomas says that one of the most becoming hats on all men is this Persian lamb headgear which was given to him by one of the fierce tribal chiefs in the mountainous country of Afghanistan, 6
    - A DAY WITH DAY - On a month-long, 3,500-mile trip by native dhow from the Persian Gulf to Zanzibar, theme of the fourth installment of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (in full color, CBS-TV network, Friday, March 27th, 8:00-9:00 p.m., EST), Thomas stops off at the forbidden port of Mukalla on the South Arabian coast to chat with Wendy Day, the daughter of famed Clarence ("Life with Father" ) Day, who is the only American woman of four white women in residence there. Miss Day, who is married to a British fisheries officer, will be seen in one of the sequences of the March 27th shows, which is sponsored by the United Motors System and Delco-Remy Division of General Motors, 7
    - Note: [press release] A DAY WITH DAY - On a month-long, 3,500-mile trip by native dhow from the Persian Gulf to Zanzibar, theme of the fourth installment of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (in full color, CBS-TV network, Friday, March 27th, 8:00-9:00 p.m., EST), Thomas stops off at the forbidden port of Mukalla on the South Arabian coast to chat with Wendy Day, the daughter of famed Clarence ("Life with Father" ) Day, who is the only American woman of four white women in residence there. Miss Day, who is married to a British fisheries officer, will be seen in one of the sequences of the March 27th shows, which is sponsored by the United Motors System and Delco-Remy Division of General Motors, 8
    - DHOW-AGER OF THE SEA - Ancient Arabian sailing vessel, or dhow, is tied up in the strange port of Mukalla in Southern Arabia while Lowell Thomas and his production crew photographed scenes for the fourth edition of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas," which will be beamed over the CBS-TV network Friday, March 27, 8:00-9:00 p.m., EST. Following the northwest monsoon trade winds, the dhow, which is one of the silent stars of the March 27th show, made the 3,500-mile trip from Bahrein on the Persian Gulf to the spice island of Zanzibar off Africa's east coast in a month. Many strange ports of call visited by the dhow were covered by the Thomas cameramen and will be seen in the next "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas," which is sponsored by the United Motors System and Delco-Remy Division of General Motors, 9
    - Note: [press release] DHOW-AGER OF THE SEA - Ancient Arabian sailing vessel, or dhow, is tied up in the strange port of Mukalla in Southern Arabia while Lowell Thomas and his production crew photographed scenes for the fourth edition of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas," which will be beamed over the CBS-TV network Friday, March 27, 8:00-9:00 p.m., EST. Following the northwest monsoon trade winds, the dhow, which is one of the silent stars of the March 27th show, made the 3,500-mile trip from Bahrein on the Persian Gulf to the spice island of Zanzibar off Africa's east coast in a month. Many strange ports of call visited by the dhow were covered by the Thomas cameramen and will be seen in the next "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas," which is sponsored by the United Motors System and Delco-Remy Division of General Motors, 10
    - [Lowell Thomas and a man on a ship during his High Adventure from the Persian Gulf to Zanzibar], 11
    - [Lowell Thomas and a man sitting on a ship during his High Adventure from the Persian Gulf to Zanzibar], 12
    - [Lowell Thomas standing next to a man on a donkey; taken during Lowell Thomas's High Adventure from the Persian Gulf to Zanzibar], 13
  - Subject files: High Adventure with Lowell Thomas (From the Persian Gulf to Zanzibar), 1959 March; 7 (Box 1548)
    - Dear Ed Heffron, Three of these pictures were taken on an expedition in Australia. The old boy with the white beard and the heavy eyebrows is an Australian Drover. He was a well known character in the Australian Outback. Which I had a copy of that one. I've forgotten what they call the little animals on my arm. They actually look like dragons, and evidently are rather rare. We encountered them deep in the interior of Australia when we were on an expedition. The man chatting with me in the picture where I'm sitting on the front of a Land Rover, is an Australian film producer named Lee Robinson who was directing the making of our film. Behind us is what the Australians consider one of the wonders of the world, Ayers Rock. They say it is the largest single rock in the world and is several miles in circumference. The one with the young lady was made in a palace in the Atlas Mountains, in Morocco. And the one where I'm sitting at a table with a mask beside me was made in what was known as the Belgian Congo on the shores of Lake Albert. Sincerely, Lowell Thomas; P.S. All the pictures were probably all taken in 1958, 1